The communication models.
So we have a basic sender-receiver model.
All right.
So the sender has an idea, has to put it
into some message.
So they encode.
That's what encode is.
Put that idea into a message.
Then they have to transmit it,
actually send it.
The receiver will get it.
and decode, make sense of it.
So that's the basic sender-receiver model.
There are two more steps they added for
interactive.
We have acknowledged.
So the receiver got the message.
Doesn't mean they understand it.
Agree with it.
They simply got it.
So if you have lots of
stakeholders and you use
Microsoft, office to do
the little red receipt thing.
That's an acknowledgement.
That's your CYA, but it does not mean that
the receiver understood the message.
So they added this last one here.
Feedback.
Feedback response.
So the receiver will then encode their
message and send it back to you.
So make sure to write this down somewhere.
It is always the sender that is
responsible for making sure the receiver
understands the message.
That's why feedback is so important.
You get feedback to see
if they understand what
you were trying to send
out in the first place.
All right, I do want to point out
something else before we're done.
You see all these little
places there are called
noise that's anything that
can interrupt a message.
So you see over here, current emotional
states of the sender or receiver.
But other things, we've already talked
about barriers.
Lack of background information,
languages, ages.
There are all kinds of
things that can create noise,
interrupt the message from
actually being sent or understood.
So always know that it is the sender's
response.
responsibility to make sure the message is
understood.